PÉTER FÜLÖP

Junior Software Developer

My online CV!

mrpeterfulop@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/peter-fulop +36 30 656 1900



ABOUT ME

My name is Péter Fülöp, I am 29 years old. I live in a small town, named Körmend, in Vas county. I have working experiences as a mechanical technician, CAD-designer, and photographer as well. I have always been interested in automatization, programming, and simplifying things. During my previous jobs, I had the opportunity to simplify processes by introducing small automations. Initially, I used excel macros, later I started to learn about VBA and userForms. I created price and offer calculators, inventory management application, cutting optimizer app, respectively I was working on a complex company management system as well, for handling the projects of the company, for managing the orders, clients, partners, and deliveries. Later, I started learning web development and the basics of programming on my own, and after 2 years of school, I graduated as a software developer.

PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS & PROJECTS At Coding Sans

Internal auction management system and online auction platform

Participation in the development of internal auction software and online auction platform. Agile development in a team, Jira ticket management. Used technologies: Node.js, NextJS, PostgreSQL, Apollo & GraphQL, RabbitMQ, Redis.

Achievements

• BULK ITEM IMPORT SERVICE

Bulk item import function from excel file. The user had the opportunity to import data from an excel file (.xls, .xlsx, .ods) into the database based on a predefined schema. Before uploading, the excel files were stored in an AWS Bucket, from which they were scanned. The processing was preceded by a 4-step validation protocol, where a service examined the uploaded file in terms of form and content. The column names and the data associated with the columns were checked, which had to meet the formal requirements defined in the database. If necessary, it examined duplications, and the existence of all data referring to the database was verified. It was also possible to log the errors per line, so the user could see exactly how many rows of the uploaded excel table contained the error. The user had the opportunity to generate an empty template based on the schema, the headers of which met the formal requirements.

SPECIALITIES

Backend heavy full-stack development

SKILLS

C#, .NET, nodeJS, Typescript, Javascript, Fastify, Express, Apollo & GraphQL, Docker, CI/CD, RabbitMQ, Prisma, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Microsoft SQL Server, Amazon S3, AWS Lambda, Terraform, Heroku, Firebase, Excel VBA, React, NextJS, MUI, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Sass

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coding Sans Zrt.

Junior software developer 05/2022 - present

Photographer

self employed photographer 2020 -2022

Breitenbach Kft. Metal Industry

CAD-designer & Production preparatory 2017 - 2020

ADA Hungária Kft. Furniture Industry

CAD-designer 2014 - 2017

EDUCATION

Vas Megyei SZC Rázsó Imre Vocational School

Software developer - adult education (C#, .NET, JavaScript, PHP, MSSQL) 2020 - 2022

Mechanical Industry and IT Technical Vocational School - Szombathely

Mechanical technician and CAD-designer, CNC programmer 2012 - 2014

PDF GENERATION

PDF generation logic based on html templates, with dynamic properties, like page breaks, unique headers & footers, sequential numbers, and content checking via encrypting. PDF storing in S3 Bucket, AWS Lambda function for PDF generation.

At Breitenbach Kft.

• Internal projects achievements

Production, preparation, and data management solutions

PROJECT MANAGER APP

A complex, company-managed internal system for managing running projects, orders, registering partner companies and employees data, organising deliveries, with customizable roles for each department. Automatic generation of order PDFs and sending of emails. Implemented in Excel VBA and Userform UI.

CUTTING OPTIMIZER APP

A solution for assessing the material requirements of steel production, which calculated the expected material requirements for the order based on the known material lengths and cross-sections, and exported a cutting list for the production in PDF format. We had the opportunity to specify the minimum residue per thread, the cutting sheet thickness. The data was imported from the program in excel format, and in the beta version it was also able to calculate from existing stock. Implemented in Excel VBA and Userform UI.

WAREHOUSE STOCK APP

The goal was to create a simple stock register program, which enables the inventory of incoming products (fasteners, straps, wood materials). In case of critically low inventory, it warned the user which products needed to be ordered. The removal from the warehouse was also tracked: who, when, what, and for which project number the given products were removed. It was possible to create a summary statement, with PDF generation. Implemented in Excel VBA and Userform UI.